Connecticut Training School for Nurses
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Training School for Nurses, Alumnae Association Records.
1891-1964.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center
Connecticut Training School for Nurses Alumnae Association.
1 linear foot.
MSS19960021
The Connecticut Training School (CTS) for Nurses opened in 1873 and closed in 1926. The Connecticut Training School for Nurses Alumnae Association was formed in January 1891 and was dissolved in 1964.
History
Established in 1873, the Connecticut Training School for Nurses (CTS) offered the first training program for nurses in the state. Many of the early leaders of Connecticut's nursing profession studied there before the school closed in 1926.
Scope and Content
The records document the activities of the school's graduates and include minutes of the association's meetings (1891-1964), annual reports, and financial records.
Arrangement
Series I: Records ( 1891-1964 ) include annual reports, minutes, and financial materials arranged alphabetically by document type.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to nursing education in Connecticut. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
Connecticut Training School for Nurses--Alumni and alumnae.; New Haven Hospital (New Haven, Conn.).
Places:
New Haven (Conn.)--Education.
Subjects:
Nurses--Study and teaching--Connecticut--New Haven.
Document Types:
Publications.; Financial Records.; Minutes.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated in 1996 by Dr. Eleanor Hermann.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Records, 1891-1964
  - Accounts (year end, Endowment Funds), 1946-1964 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report (18th), 1892 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report (26th), 1900 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Cash Book, 1938-1964 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Cash Book, 1958-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - History, ca. 1905 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1938-1957 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1891-1905 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1906-1915 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1915-1923 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1923-1926 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1926-1929 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1930-1934 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1935-1936 (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1939 (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1942-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1946-1953 (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1954-1964 (Box 2:, Folder 21)